"use strict";(self.webpackChunkquiz_app=self.webpackChunkquiz_app||[]).push([[7396],{7396:e=>{e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"What is Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE)?","answers":[{"text":"A container orchestration platform","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A cloud-based database service","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A serverless computing environment","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A machine learning platform","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What container runtime is commonly used with GKE?","answers":[{"text":"Docker","isCorrect":true},{"text":"rkt","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Containerd","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Podman","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which command is used to create a GKE cluster using the Google Cloud SDK?","answers":[{"text":"gcloud create-cluster","isCorrect":false},{"text":"gcloud deploy-cluster","isCorrect":false},{"text":"gcloud container clusters create","isCorrect":true},{"text":"gcloud build-cluster","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a node pool in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"A group of GKE clusters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A set of interconnected Kubernetes nodes","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A dynamic set of Compute Engine VM instances for running containers","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A reserved IP address range for GKE clusters","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does GKE manage the underlying Kubernetes control plane?","answers":[{"text":"Manually by users","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Through the Kubernetes Dashboard","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Automatically as a managed service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By connecting to an external control plane","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which Google Cloud service can be used for deploying containerized applications to GKE?","answers":[{"text":"Google Cloud Storage","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Google Cloud Functions","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Google Cloud Build","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Google Cloud SQL","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a Kubernetes Pod in the context of GKE?","answers":[{"text":"A set of interconnected GKE nodes","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A single unit of deployment that runs one or more containers","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A reserved IP address for external access to GKE clusters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A secure network channel between GKE clusters","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How is automatic scaling achieved in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"By adjusting the size of the Kubernetes control plane","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By manually adding or removing nodes from the cluster","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Through the Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA)","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By adjusting the size of the Docker containers","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is GKE Autopilot mode?","answers":[{"text":"A manual scaling mode for GKE clusters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A mode where Google manages the cluster control plane, and users manage the nodes","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A fully managed mode where both the control plane and nodes are automatically managed by Google","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A mode designed for on-premises Kubernetes deployments","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which Kubernetes resource is used to expose a service outside of the cluster in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"Ingress","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Pod","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ReplicaSet","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a Kubernetes ConfigMap in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"To store confidential information like passwords","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To provide a way to inject configuration data into Pods","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To define network policies for GKE clusters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To schedule periodic tasks in GKE","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which Kubernetes resource is used to ensure high availability of applications in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"Pod","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Service","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ReplicaSet","isCorrect":true},{"text":"ConfigMap","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you perform a rolling update of a deployment in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"By deleting and recreating the entire deployment","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By manually updating each Pod individually","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By updating the Pod template of the deployment","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By scaling the deployment to zero and then scaling it back up","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the role of a Kubernetes DaemonSet in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"To manage secrets and sensitive information","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To ensure that a specific number of Pods are running on each node","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To expose a service outside of the cluster","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To scale Pods automatically based on demand","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does GKE handle application logging and monitoring?","answers":[{"text":"Through manual configuration of third-party monitoring tools","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using built-in logging and monitoring features like Stackdriver","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By exporting logs and metrics to an external data store","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By relying on Kubernetes default logging mechanisms","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of GKE node auto-repair?","answers":[{"text":"To automatically replace failed nodes in the cluster","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To resize the cluster based on demand","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To upgrade the Kubernetes control plane version","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To automatically scale the number of nodes in the cluster","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you secure communication between Pods in a GKE cluster?","answers":[{"text":"By using unencrypted HTTP for communication","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By relying on the security features of the underlying VM instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using Kubernetes Network Policies","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By disabling network communication between Pods","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a Kubernetes Service in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"To store and manage configuration data for applications","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To expose a set of Pods as a network service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To run background tasks in a distributed manner","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To deploy applications in a containerized environment","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does GKE support rolling updates without downtime?","answers":[{"text":"By manually pausing traffic during updates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By routing traffic only to updated Pods during the update process","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By stopping and restarting the entire cluster during updates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By redirecting traffic to a backup cluster during updates","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a Kubernetes StatefulSet in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"To ensure a specific number of replicas are running","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To deploy applications with stateless architecture","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To manage stateful applications with unique network identities","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To provide persistent storage for GKE clusters","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you expose a GKE service to external traffic?","answers":[{"text":"By using an internal load balancer","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By configuring a firewall rule for external access","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using an external load balancer","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By exposing the service directly through the node\'s external IP address","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of Kubernetes RBAC in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"To manage access control for Google Cloud resources","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To control access to the Kubernetes control plane","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To secure communication between Pods","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To manage resource quotas for GKE clusters","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does GKE handle automatic node upgrades?","answers":[{"text":"By requiring manual intervention for every upgrade","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By automatically upgrading nodes without user intervention","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By pausing the cluster during the upgrade process","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By downgrading nodes to the previous version in case of issues","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you consider when designing a multi-zone GKE cluster for high availability?","answers":[{"text":"Zonal clusters are more cost-effective","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Multi-zone clusters provide better fault tolerance","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Zonal clusters have lower network latency","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Multi-zone clusters have lower resource utilization","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In a scenario where you need to scale your GKE nodes based on demand, which GKE feature would you use?","answers":[{"text":"Kubernetes ConfigMap","isCorrect":false},{"text":"GKE Autopilot mode","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Kubernetes Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA)","isCorrect":false},{"text":"GKE node auto-repair","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You have an application with persistent storage requirements. Which Kubernetes resource in GKE is suitable for managing stateful applications?","answers":[{"text":"Pod","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Service","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ReplicaSet","isCorrect":false},{"text":"StatefulSet","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How can you secure communication between Pods in a GKE cluster?","answers":[{"text":"By using unencrypted HTTP for communication","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By relying on the security features of the underlying VM instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using Kubernetes Network Policies","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By disabling network communication between Pods","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to expose a GKE service to external traffic. Which method should you use?","answers":[{"text":"Internal load balancer","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Firewall rule for external access","isCorrect":false},{"text":"External load balancer","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Expose the service directly through the node\'s external IP address","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of Kubernetes RBAC in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"To manage access control for Google Cloud resources","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To control access to the Kubernetes control plane","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To secure communication between Pods","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To manage resource quotas for GKE clusters","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You need to perform a rolling update of a deployment in GKE without downtime. What approach should you take?","answers":[{"text":"Delete and recreate the entire deployment","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Manually update each Pod individually","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Update the Pod template of the deployment","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Scale the deployment to zero and then scale it back up","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In a scenario where you want to manage secrets and sensitive information in GKE, which Kubernetes resource is appropriate?","answers":[{"text":"Pod","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Service","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ReplicaSet","isCorrect":false},{"text":"DaemonSet","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How does GKE handle application logging and monitoring?","answers":[{"text":"Through manual configuration of third-party monitoring tools","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using built-in logging and monitoring features like Stackdriver","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By exporting logs and metrics to an external data store","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By relying on Kubernetes default logging mechanisms","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to ensure high availability of applications in GKE. Which Kubernetes resource should you use?","answers":[{"text":"Pod","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Service","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ReplicaSet","isCorrect":true},{"text":"ConfigMap","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of GKE Autopilot mode?","answers":[{"text":"Manual scaling mode for GKE clusters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Mode where Google manages the cluster control plane, and users manage the nodes","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Fully managed mode where both the control plane and nodes are automatically managed by Google","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Mode designed for on-premises Kubernetes deployments","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to perform a rolling update of a GKE deployment without downtime. How can you achieve this?","answers":[{"text":"Manually pause traffic during updates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Route traffic only to updated Pods during the update process","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Stop and restart the entire cluster during updates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Redirect traffic to a backup cluster during updates","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a Kubernetes StatefulSet in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"Ensure a specific number of replicas are running","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Deploy applications with stateless architecture","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Manage stateful applications with unique network identities","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Provide persistent storage for GKE clusters","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to use workload scheduling and identity management for Kubernetes Pods in GKE. What feature should you leverage?","answers":[{"text":"Kubernetes Ingress","isCorrect":false},{"text":"GKE Workload Identity","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Kubernetes Helm","isCorrect":false},{"text":"GKE Autopilot mode","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does GKE handle automatic node upgrades?","answers":[{"text":"Require manual intervention for every upgrade","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Automatically upgrade nodes without user intervention","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Pause the cluster during the upgrade process","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Downgrade nodes to the previous version in case of issues","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to expose a GKE service to external traffic. Which method should you use?","answers":[{"text":"Internal load balancer","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Firewall rule for external access","isCorrect":false},{"text":"External load balancer","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Expose the service directly through the node\'s external IP address","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In a scenario where you need to control access to the Kubernetes control plane in GKE, what feature should you use?","answers":[{"text":"Kubernetes RBAC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Kubernetes Ingress","isCorrect":false},{"text":"GKE Autopilot mode","isCorrect":false},{"text":"GKE node auto-repair","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to implement automatic repair of failed nodes in a GKE cluster. Which feature should you enable?","answers":[{"text":"GKE Autopilot mode","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Kubernetes Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA)","isCorrect":false},{"text":"GKE node auto-repair","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Kubernetes StatefulSet","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In a scenario where you need to manage access control for Google Cloud resources in GKE, what feature should you leverage?","answers":[{"text":"Kubernetes RBAC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"GKE Autopilot mode","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Google Cloud IAM","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Kubernetes Network Policies","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to use a managed mode where both the control plane and nodes are automatically managed by Google in GKE. What mode should you choose?","answers":[{"text":"GKE Autopilot mode","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Manual scaling mode","isCorrect":false},{"text":"User-managed mode","isCorrect":false},{"text":"On-premises mode","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you ensure high availability of applications in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"By running all Pods on a single node","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using Kubernetes ConfigMap","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By deploying applications in a ReplicaSet","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By using Kubernetes StatefulSet","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to use Kubernetes Network Policies to control communication between Pods in GKE. What should you configure?","answers":[{"text":"Firewall rules at the VM instance level","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Routing rules at the GKE cluster level","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Rules at the Pod level to define allowed traffic","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Access control at the GKE node level","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You need to deploy an application that requires unique network identities for each instance. Which Kubernetes resource in GKE is suitable for this scenario?","answers":[{"text":"Pod","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Service","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ReplicaSet","isCorrect":false},{"text":"StatefulSet","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You want to use GKE for running serverless workloads, and you prefer a fully managed mode. What GKE feature should you choose?","answers":[{"text":"GKE Autopilot mode","isCorrect":true},{"text":"User-managed mode","isCorrect":false},{"text":"On-premises mode","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Manual scaling mode","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a Kubernetes DaemonSet in GKE?","answers":[{"text":"Manage secrets and sensitive information","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ensure that a specific number of Pods are running on each node","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Expose a service outside of the cluster","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Scale Pods automatically based on demand","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You want to use Kubernetes RBAC to manage access control for Google Cloud resources in GKE. What should you configure?","answers":[{"text":"Access control at the GKE node level","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Firewall rules at the VM instance level","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Roles and role bindings within the Kubernetes cluster","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Routing rules at the GKE cluster level","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You need to expose a set of Pods as a network service in GKE. What Kubernetes resource should you use?","answers":[{"text":"Pod","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"ReplicaSet","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ConfigMap","isCorrect":false}]}]')}}]);